<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-15T13:50:07+02:00</updated><id>https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">MVP</title><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m7/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MVP" /><published>2022-01-10T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-01-10T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m7</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m7/">&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#watch-our-demo-here&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-watch-our-demo-here&quot;&gt;Watch Our Demo Here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#technical-aspects&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-technical-aspects&quot;&gt;Technical aspects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#description&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;watch-our-demo-here&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1zl0-EFyQmQ9nzR-BYPpbEAQQmItKTBNO/view&quot;&gt;Watch Our Demo Here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;technical-aspects&quot;&gt;Technical aspects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unreal Engine &amp;amp; its Assets Marketplace&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C++ &amp;amp; Blueprint Visual Scripting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SteamVR&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oculus Quest 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main idea of this game was subject to a lot of research and brainstorming among our team. Our goal was to stand out regarding the story and the setup, but we always kept the validation aspects in mind, even though we had generally planned the environment ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our interviewees reacted well to the idea of a bite-sized horror game, confirming the fact that it is a niche, unsaturated market that is in demand. We decided to remain with Steam as our main distribution platform, as they provide an environment to self publish games easily accessible by interested buyers. They also perpetually showcase new games and organise themed sale events, allowing new indie games to be discovered. Moreover, SteamVR is the leading tool used to interact with PC VR headsets and it abstracts away most hardware-specific behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the game bite-sized is an extremely important aspect, as we confirmed that a variety of player archetypes would be interested in short experiences: hardcore gamers who want to take a break and casual gamers who just want to have an interesting experience, but not spend too much time or money on it. We have, on the other hand, reached the conclusion that the horror aspect is not absolutely necessary for our game to be successful as it is a matter of taste, but we still believe that the horror genre is a good starting point. It lends itself very well to short experiences, leveraging the concept of “fear of the unknown” when leaving certain elements unexplained, for instance. This allows the development team more leeway when making potential mistakes on a first game, while not severely impacting the quality of our final product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite not being able to obtain hard user validation for this information, we still believe that VR is the way to go. Our business’ premise is that VR is an untapped market and there have been precedents of successful indie VR horror games such as “The Room VR: A Dark Matter”, as shown in our market research section. We were unable to obtain solid feedback on this matter due to the fact that any interviewees who already own a VR headset would naturally have no aversion to this aspect, while any who do not already own one would clearly not buy a headset for this experience alone. VR headset ownership will continue to grow worldwide in the following years as the concept becomes both more popular and cheaper to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/AR VR stats.jpg&quot; title=&quot;AR VR stats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AR VR stats.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MVP follows a structure familiar to anyone who has played puzzle games before: solve a puzzle, move to the next room, repeat, while placing this flow into context: the player has a compelling reason to solve the puzzle and move forward - they are trying to escape the Murder Hotel. This first game contains three fully-playable levels, each taking place on a different floor of the house. Details can be found in the wireframe/game design section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of improvements that we want to incorporate into Murder Hotel before it is ready for release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The backstory is not clear enough as-is: our only mention of the Murder Hotel is at the end and we don’t believe it’s clear enough to the player what they are trying to escape from. Players gain this information from the synopsis, but we think that it would be more immersive if there were bits of lore scattered around the level that can be found while searching for clues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playtesting has also underlined a number of technical flaws that need to be addressed, and a few design flaws: more clarity needs to be added to certain elements. We need to make sure that the player knows exactly what they managed to do at any point in time and visually and auditorily reward them for it, accentuating their progress. There are also a few elements that don’t work as well based on player height and instinctive behaviour, as detailed in the playtesting section. Once this game is released, we intend to begin work on our next one, taking into account sales, reviews and any other newly available information.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Milestone 7" /></entry><entry><title type="html">First Sell</title><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m8/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Sell" /><published>2022-01-10T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-01-10T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m8/">&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#interviews&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-interviews&quot;&gt;Interviews&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#george-22&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-george-22&quot;&gt;George, 22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dan-25&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-dan-25&quot;&gt;Dan, 25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#interview-conclusions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-interview-conclusions&quot;&gt;Interview conclusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#playtest-impressions--final-conclusions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-playtest-impressions--final-conclusions&quot;&gt;Playtest impressions &amp;amp; Final conclusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;interviews&quot;&gt;Interviews&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of our friends own a VR headset and they were both interested in trying our MVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;george-22&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1uZ8DQPmqCKw5R6CqyZ9qgeBJin1nkZpd/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;George, 22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was the most frustrating moment or aspect of what you just played?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The progress is not clear enough at times - e.g.: In the Attic level, the fact that the key is hidden inside the blue book could’ve been more obvious for the player&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The in-game movement, or perhaps the collisions, should be improved&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was your favourite moment or aspect of what you just played?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The music &amp;amp; the overall atmosphere support the feeling of immersion&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;VR was a big bonus regarding this subject - he is not a big fan of similar games on PC&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Was there anything you wanted to do that you couldn’t?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More interaction with the environment would’ve been nice - e.g.: doors, random objects around the house, chairs etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you had a magic wand to wave, and you could change, add, or remove anything from the experience, what would it be?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Implement an inventory for having better access to the oil lamp, lantern and other useful items - the visual interface should allow you to grab whichever object you prefer&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What were you doing in the experience?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Goal: exploration and problem solving, mostly trial &amp;amp; error&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The atmosphere is pretty great already&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Simple yet challenging puzzles - high potential if the interaction were improved&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Recommended for one-time play for fun&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would you be interested in more similar games?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A pack of 6-8 games would be great, perhaps priced around 30€&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dan-25&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/16ePETo8FGLoMl4I77fP1Z78jZ3-YWpyJ/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Dan, 25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was the most frustrating moment or aspect of what you just played?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The ending of the first level was not clear enough and created the sensation of feeling lost&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was your favourite moment or aspect of what you just played?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The puzzles are not as easy to complete as they seem - they require a good analysis &amp;amp; thinking process&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Was there anything you wanted to do that you couldn’t?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“I would’ve loved interacting with the pool cue”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you had a magic wand to wave, and you could change, add, or remove anything from the experience, what would it be?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The house seemed a bit “empty” - would populate it more with different interactable objects&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What were you doing in the experience?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Realistic experience, quite like you’re the protagonist of a movie and you have to find clues in order to advance throughout your journey&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Enjoyable horror experience, nice jumpscares, overall potential&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Loved the fact the outdoor scene was explorable quite like an open world&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;interview-conclusions&quot;&gt;Interview conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final version of our game should implement more graphical validations regarding the progress. For example, during the first level of the game, we have to clarify the fact that the book contains the key to the door since neither of our users understood that. Stating this via the user interface and adding the key to the inventory would improve the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should focus on allowing the user to interact more with the environment. Both our testers declared they would desire more possibilities of interaction with the objects present in the scenario. They told us they were willing to move chairs, open doors, grab the pool cue etc, but weren’t able to. We understand this aspect was frustrating and negatively impacts the overall experience, but we have chosen to focus on implementing puzzles and creating a heavy atmosphere rather than making sure each asset is interactable in this early development stage. We will keep this aspect in mind while developing the final product since it contravenes with the immersion supported by using VR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere is well received by a casual player. The users enjoyed the music, and it created the intended result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inventory placeholder system where a player can teleport the oil lamp and flashlight to their hand is not as immersive or intuitive as attaching said items to their belt. By doing this, players can access important items by physically reaching for them on a utility belt that functions like an inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;playtest-impressions--final-conclusions&quot;&gt;Playtest impressions &amp;amp; Final conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Players had difficulty figuring out that the blue book they picked up contains a key to the door in the attic level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Players had difficulty associating the trap door asset we chose with an actual trap door/doorway. This can be easily fixed by finding a different asset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Players tended to stop interacting with doors after a certain number of attempts, making the way to progress become unclear. The issue is likely design related, as our levels have a number of doors that cannot be interacted with, essentially training the player to ignore them. Our levels should be redesigned with doors in mind as an element that should spark interest, not be glossed over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were certain areas where tall players would accidentally put their head through the ceiling, these areas should be re-scaled to accommodate different heights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A certain doorway proved difficult to cross if the players accidentally physically moved away from their standing point in real life. This is a technically complex issue, because it depends on VR tracking behaviour, but the issue could be minimised by making the doorway wider and/or making the player’s collider smaller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puzzles need to be extremely clear, and of a medium complexity. Having a VR headset on for extended periods of time is very tiring, and we don’t want our players to spend huge amounts of time in our game anyway, as it would contradict our business plan. This means that puzzles should not be too complicated to solve without a piece of paper, and the horror atmosphere already puts pressure on our player.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Milestone 8" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Market Research</title><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m6/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Market Research" /><published>2021-12-13T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-12-13T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m6</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m6/">&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#intro&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#general-vr-only-overview&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-general-vr-only-overview&quot;&gt;General VR-only overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#main-vr-competition-based-on-the-genre&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-main-vr-competition-based-on-the-genre&quot;&gt;Main VR competition based on the genre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#competitors-market-share&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-competitors-market-share&quot;&gt;Competitors’ market share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#our-potential-market-share&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-our-potential-market-share&quot;&gt;Our potential market share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-value-of-our-market-share&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-value-of-our-market-share&quot;&gt;The value of our market share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#conclusion&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our target customers are VR headset owners, users of the Steam platform, which are passionate about puzzle &amp;amp; horror games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As statistics show, &lt;a href=&quot;https://backlinko.com/steam-users&quot;&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt; is a very successful platform:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;~120 million monthly active players&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;~62.6 million people use Steam on a daily basis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;31.3 billion hours of playtime in 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Steam survey data suggests that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.roadtovr.com/monthly-connected-headsets-steam-3-million-march-2021/&quot;&gt;~3 million users&lt;/a&gt; (2.4%) own VR headsets, but this market is enjoying a rapidly growing interest rate, with hardware prices getting lower and quality getting better over time. As of 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techjury.net/blog/virtual-reality-statistics/#gref&quot;&gt;171 million VR headsets&lt;/a&gt; are owned by consumers globally and this number is expected to keep growing rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video game industry tends to have a different behaviour than other industries, mainly because it is very developed (even overly developed at times), there is rarely a truly innovative and genuine idea, and it is almost impossible to keep track of all the similarities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the reason why we have tried to pick a balanced amount of main competitors in the VR field, being very selective after identifying and analysing a lot of games, but also taking into consideration games focused solely on the horror or puzzle genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As trying to determine the approximate number of players / competitors in our targeted market, we have decided to conduct two researches: one that tackles the general overview concerning the VR-only market on Steam and one that analyses our cherry-picked main VR competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;general-vr-only-overview&quot;&gt;General VR-only overview&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5187 VR-only games available for buying today on Steam
3 million Steam users that own a VR headset
⇒ 3 million players / 5187 games&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;main-vr-competition-based-on-the-genre&quot;&gt;Main VR competition based on the genre&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/414340/Hellblade_Senuas_Sacrifice/&quot;&gt;Hellblade: Senua’s Sacrifice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release date: 8 Aug, 2017&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An award winning puzzle-horror game with combat elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It has introduced VR support as an update in 2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/916840/The_Walking_Dead_Saints__Sinners/&quot;&gt;The Walking Dead: Saints &amp;amp; Sinners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release date: 23 Jan, 2020&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A narrative-driven VR horror game built around hard decisions that the player has to make&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is a VR-only game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/739630/Phasmophobia/&quot;&gt;Phasmophobia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release date: 18 Sep, 2020&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phasmophobia is an extremely successful indie game centred around ghost hunting experiences that take place in different locations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is available on both PC and VR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1104380/The_Room_VR_A_Dark_Matter/&quot;&gt;The Room VR: A Dark Matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release date: 26 Mar, 2020&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even though the game is puzzle-centred, the music, the lighting and the context create an oppressive atmosphere&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Available only on VR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/242760/The_Forest/&quot;&gt;The Forest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release date: 30 Apr, 2018&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Survival horror simulator taking place in a forest where cannibals live&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Features both PC and VR supports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;⇒ 3 million players / 5 horror or puzzle competitor games on VR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;competitors-market-share&quot;&gt;Competitors’ market share&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/competition market share.jpg&quot; title=&quot;competition market share.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;competition market share.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;our-potential-market-share&quot;&gt;Our potential market share&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our competition consists mainly of AAA titles or sensationally successful indie games, our potential market share estimation isn’t that comparable to theirs. So, taking all of those things into consideration, we have objectively estimated the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/potential market share.jpg&quot; title=&quot;potential market share.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;potential market share.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-value-of-our-market-share&quot;&gt;The value of our market share&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As statistics suggest, global VR video gaming revenues reached &lt;a href=&quot;https://techjury.net/blog/virtual-reality-statistics/#gref&quot;&gt;$22.9B&lt;/a&gt; in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the validation process has highlighted, players prefer buying a game that is on sale rather than paying the full price. As such, we’re planning on implementing frequent minimal sales and our calculations take into consideration the interval of 16-18€.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/potential market share value.jpg&quot; title=&quot;potential market share value.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;potential market share value.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conducted research has put into light few interesting aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Availability is a key-factor regarding the number of copies sold. The two VR-only games (both indie and AAA) among our competitors have recorded significantly fewer downloads than the ones supporting both PC and VR gameplays. This particular insight motivated us to further investigate the possibility of also implementing a PC version of the game besides our main VR focus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The popularity of the Steam platform complies to our needs and offers us an important market opening&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The growing interest towards VR technologies represents a notable advantage for our business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Milestone 6" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Validation 2</title><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Validation 2" /><published>2021-12-06T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-12-06T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m5/">&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#interviews&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-interviews&quot;&gt;Interviews&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#luca-23&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-luca-23&quot;&gt;Luca, 23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dan-25&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-dan-25&quot;&gt;Dan, 25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ilaria-22&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-ilaria-22&quot;&gt;Ilaria, 22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#interview-conclusions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-interview-conclusions&quot;&gt;Interview Conclusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lead-generation-and-collection&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lead-generation-and-collection&quot;&gt;Lead Generation and Collection&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#newsletter&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-newsletter&quot;&gt;Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#our-adobe-xd-landing-page&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-our-adobe-xd-landing-page&quot;&gt;Our Adobe XD Landing Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#backstory&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#results&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#test-conclusions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-test-conclusions&quot;&gt;Test Conclusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;interviews&quot;&gt;Interviews&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;luca-23&quot;&gt;Luca, 23&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you own a Steam account?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many games do you own on Steam?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About 15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you prefer shorter, low-commitment games or longer, more involved games?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mostly prefers shorter games, but did not give a decisive answer. He has a strong preference towards shorter play sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How often do you play video games?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About twice a week, 2 hours or so at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What games do you currently play?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Civilization VI, Witch It&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re playing video games, how often is it a horror game?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rarely plays horror games. They are not his main focus, but he did express that a game being part of the horror genre is not necessarily a disadvantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes you decide if you are going to buy a game full price or wait for a sale?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An indie game would have to be very good and have a reputation for him to pay 20 euros. 10-15 euros is the range he is willing to spend on an “unproved” indie game. For an AAA or other high budget game, he is only comfortable spending up to 35 euros. Anything above these prices (exceptional situations aside) will be bought on sale). Game length is not a consideration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever buy games just because they are on sale?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not just because it is on sale, but if a game he was mildly interested in goes on sale, he will likely buy it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever played a game in VR? If so, what game(s)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes, Beat Saber and I Expect You to Die. He enjoyed them both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you be excited to try a bite-sized puzzle-horror game in VR?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes, the puzzle aspect is more exciting to Luca than the horror aspect, and the game being short is a good fit for his busy schedule at the office. The answer mostly depends on puzzle quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dan-25&quot;&gt;Dan, 25&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you own a Steam account?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many games do you own on Steam?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About 18.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you prefer shorter, low-commitment games or longer, more involved games?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prefers high commitment games and regularly plays MMORPGs, but will often take a break to play a shorter game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How often do you play video games?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quite often, pretty much every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What games do you currently play?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;World of Warcraft, Guilty Gear Strive, Phasmophobia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re playing video games, how often is it a horror game?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very often, most of the shorter games he plays between raids are horror games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes you decide if you are going to buy a game full price or wait for a sale?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He generally buys indie games full price, but never spends the full price on AAA games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever buy games just because they are on sale?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes, mostly because a friend tells him about them, and he buys the game in order to play together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever played a game in VR? If so, what game(s)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes, Beat Saber, Ping Pong and Phasmophobia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you be excited to try a bite-sized puzzle-horror game in VR?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes, it would be great as something to play while taking a break from World of Warcraft, and it’s a horror game as a bonus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ilaria-22&quot;&gt;Ilaria, 22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you own a Steam account?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many games do you own on Steam?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;23&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you prefer shorter, low-commitment games or longer, more involved games?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It depends on how much free time she has. When she’s busy, she will almost exclusively play short, bite-sized games, but will gladly start one requiring a significant time investment during summer vacation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How often do you play video games?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About twice a week, mostly late at night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What games do you currently play?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phasmophobia, Online board games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re playing video games, how often is it a horror game?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Almost every time, her favourite game is Phasmophobia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes you decide if you are going to buy a game full price or wait for a sale?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For an indie game, she usually pays full price up to 20 euros, and for a large-budget game a price over 40 euros will make her wait for a sale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever buy games just because they are on sale?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only if they were already wishlisted and the sale is substantial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever played a game in VR? If so, what game(s)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes, Phasmophobia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you be excited to try a bite-sized puzzle-horror game in VR?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Definitely, anything that reminds her of Phasmophobia is welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interview-conclusions&quot;&gt;Interview Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it looks like the idea of a horror game appeals to our target audience. Those who are not specifically interested in horror are still tempted by the puzzle aspect, and all the people we asked like short games, at least casually if not as their main focus. The price range we projected (about 15 euros) seems to be in the sweet spot of what people would buy at full price, and small sales will likely be enough to convince anyone who is on the fence about our product. The platform we chose seems to be welcome, since everyone we asked already uses Steam regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interviews made it clear that even if many people are interested in Murder Hotel and wishlist it, they might still need an extra incentive to buy the game. With this in mind, we will look into the idea of pricing Murder Hotel slightly above 15 euros, and implementing occasional sales, bringing the price down to what we originally thought to be a good starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, our interviewees have all tried VR games, but one of them does not actually own a headset, meaning that even if they would normally buy Murder Hotel, the hardware investment would be too much to expect as an indie developer. This lead us to believe that implementing a standard PC mode could be the way to go, while still keeping VR mode as the main focus. This two-mode architecture is similar to what Phasmophobia achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that became apparent is that we need people to recommend the game to their friends. Advertising is, of course, necessary, but what will actually convince people to buy our game is if their friends played and enjoyed it in the past. We believe that this is a good sign for our “suite of games” concept, since we benefit from the excitement generated by each new release, attracting more and more friends of those who enjoyed previous installments in the series. Our questionnaire showed that there is not much interest in game bundles, so releasing and selling these games individually is likely best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the bite-size length and play sessions appealed to everyone, we think that this should be a main focus. Similar to childrens’ TV shows, we want to make sure that play sessions are self explanatory and enjoyable even if the user has not played in a long time and doesn’t remember much. This way, it will never feel like a hassle or an annoyance to “just play for a bit”, further leaning on the casual audience: busy people who don’t have a lot of time for games and heavy gamers who want a bit of diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;lead-generation-and-collection&quot;&gt;Lead Generation and Collection&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;newsletter&quot;&gt;Newsletter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;our-adobe-xd-landing-page&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xd.adobe.com/view/d2694f4e-dadb-489f-8132-eae7c58fec24-873a/&quot;&gt;Our Adobe XD Landing Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our landing page is prototyped in XD, we needed a plugin that lets us test it. For that we used &lt;strong&gt;Useberry&lt;/strong&gt;, which captures user insights by asking them to perform quick tests on our design prototype. The tasks that were given were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 5 sec test&lt;/strong&gt;: Look at the landing page for 5 sec and write the first thing you noticed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sort the cards in the order you noticed them(the purchase button, the video previews, the game screenshot the logo of the game, the free trial, the upper menu, other elements (promotions etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Click&lt;/strong&gt;: Where would you click to purchase our product?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Click&lt;/strong&gt;: Where would you click to access our Halloween sale?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Click&lt;/strong&gt;: How about subscribing to our newsletter?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Click&lt;/strong&gt;: What about viewing our other games?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Click&lt;/strong&gt;: Can you also click on one Twitch video?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes/No&lt;/strong&gt;: Was your overall experience with our landing page good?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/0.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The 5 sec test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sort the cards in order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where would you click to purchase our product?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where would you click to access our Halloween sale?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/4.jpg&quot; title=&quot;4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How about subscribing to our newsletter?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/5.jpg&quot; title=&quot;5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What about viewing our other games?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/6.jpg&quot; title=&quot;6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you also click on one Twitch video?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/7.jpg&quot; title=&quot;7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Was your overall experience with our landing page good?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/8.jpg&quot; title=&quot;8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;test-conclusions&quot;&gt;Test Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The test results were overall great. From our limited 10 testers, we can make the following conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first thing that catches your eyes when looking at our landing page is either the logo or the video header. That is good as customers know exactly what the game is about.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When it comes to card sorting, the way our testers ordered them follows the flow we want our customers to digest information about our product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All users clicked on either trying or buying the game, no other misclicks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some people were stuck in the upper portion of the page, but most of them found the Halloween sale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most users interacted with our Newsletter ribbon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most of them were right to go in the Games section in the header.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here there was a little confusion between our video presentations and our Twitch ribbon. &lt;strong&gt;Marking the video presentations as our content can help the confusion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;90% of our testers had a good experience with the landing page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Milestone 5" /></entry><entry><title type="html">UX</title><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UX" /><published>2021-11-22T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-22T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m4/">&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#gameplay-loop&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-gameplay-loop&quot;&gt;Gameplay Loop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#user-stories&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-user-stories&quot;&gt;User Stories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#persona&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-persona&quot;&gt;Persona&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gameplay-loop&quot;&gt;Gameplay Loop&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/diagram.png&quot; title=&quot;diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;diagram.png&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;user-stories&quot;&gt;User Stories&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to write the user stories from the perpective of someone in the playable character’s shoes in order to help us create a more immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/userstories.png&quot; title=&quot;userstories.png&quot; alt=&quot;userstories.png&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;persona&quot;&gt;Persona&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Persona.png&quot; title=&quot;Persona.png&quot; alt=&quot;Persona.png&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Milestone 4" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wireframe &amp;amp; Landing Page</title><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wireframe &amp;amp; Landing Page" /><published>2021-11-15T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-15T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m3/">&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#wireframe&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-wireframe&quot;&gt;Wireframe&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#initial-inspiration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-initial-inspiration&quot;&gt;Initial Inspiration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#level-1---attic&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-level-1---attic&quot;&gt;Level 1 - Attic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#level-2---hotel&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-level-2---hotel&quot;&gt;Level 2 - Hotel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#level-3---basement&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-level-3---basement&quot;&gt;Level 3 - Basement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#landing-page&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-landing-page&quot;&gt;Landing Page&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#our-adobe-xd-landing-page&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-our-adobe-xd-landing-page&quot;&gt;Our Adobe XD Landing Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wireframe&quot;&gt;Wireframe&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The object of the game is to solve a number of puzzles and escape the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial-inspiration&quot;&gt;Initial Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/murdercastle.jpg&quot; title=&quot;murdercastle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;murdercastle.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;level-1---attic&quot;&gt;Level 1 - Attic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first level is in the attic, where H.H. Holmes has trapped you, the player. After looking around the room, you find an odd looking oil lamp. Looking around some more, a note on the desk suggests using the oil lamp on an basic “hidden text” element, serving as an immersive tutorial on how to use the oil lamp to reveal invisible text. Following the revealed instructions, it becomes clear that you should look for a key hidden in the bookcase. The key unlocks the door and you are now free to roam the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Murder_Hotel_-_Attic.png&quot; title=&quot;Murder_Hotel_-_Attic.png&quot; alt=&quot;Murder_Hotel_-_Attic.png&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Puzzle1.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;Puzzle1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Puzzle1.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;level-2---hotel&quot;&gt;Level 2 - Hotel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second level is the main hotel area, spanning two floors. Here, you are supposed to roam around while avoiding Holmes himself who appears in certain areas, either guiding you in the right direction or deterring you from reaching an objective. Holmes’ apparitions also serve as a “breadcrumb trail” towards the objective: a photograph containing the puzzle for this level. Looking at the photograph leads you to an identical area in the hotel, except for one difference. Something is missing in the actual room, and investigating it leads you to a trap door, connecting to the basement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Murder_Hotel_-_House.png&quot; title=&quot;Murder_Hotel_-_House.png&quot; alt=&quot;Murder_Hotel_-_House.png&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Puzzle2.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;Puzzle2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Puzzle2.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;level-3---basement&quot;&gt;Level 3 - Basement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and last level takes place in the basement. Looking around there is a locked door and it is hinted at that you should look for invisible writing on the wall, using the oil lamp. Once the writing is found, it leads you to a key that unlocks the door. Behind the door, there is another trap door that leads outside. Using it leads to freedom, the game is over!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Murder_Hotel_-_Basement.png&quot; title=&quot;Murder_Hotel_-_Basement.png&quot; alt=&quot;Murder_Hotel_-_Basement.png&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Puzzle3.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;Puzzle3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Puzzle3.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;landing-page&quot;&gt;Landing Page&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of our website’s landing page, we decided to get help from Adobe XD, because of its easy prototyping and the possibility to export the whole thing to HTML and CSS files or even to a React project using Anima.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;our-adobe-xd-landing-page&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xd.adobe.com/view/c18cd843-cd7c-4ad7-b545-360d96365b5a-94df/&quot;&gt;Our Adobe XD Landing Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An XD project usually starts with a defined color palette, for which we chose grey-based colors and a pop of a vibrant red.
The navigation bar contains easy to access information, including links to buying or testing the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main scrollview is composed of 5 components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The video ribbon, which contains YouTube videos that act as video presentations for our game and our work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The information ribbon, which has a short description of the product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Twitch scrollable ribbon, which shows people currently playing the game, making the product more desirable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The deal scrollable ribbon, which is composed of deals, which seem to be the number one determination of purchasing games, according the the survey conducted in M2.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The footer ribbon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Milestone 3" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Validation 1</title><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Validation 1" /><published>2021-11-08T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-08T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/m2/">&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#customer-delivery---overview&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-customer-delivery---overview&quot;&gt;Customer Delivery - Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#customer-detail---process&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-customer-detail---process&quot;&gt;Customer Detail - Process&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#customer-detail---results&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-customer-detail---results&quot;&gt;Customer Detail - Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#customer-detail---conclusions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-customer-detail---conclusions&quot;&gt;Customer Detail - Conclusions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;customer-delivery---overview&quot;&gt;Customer Delivery - Overview&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to gain more insights on what particular features of our product will appeal to our clients and how much will they interact with our game as well, we decided we needed a customer segmentation. We used &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;behavioural segmentation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for this, because of the nature of our product (a game) and because of the fact that the more we predict the purchasing decisions of our customer, the more revenue our project gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;customer-detail---process&quot;&gt;Customer Detail - Process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step was to conduct the survey, through Google Forms, and the question groups were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you own a VR headset?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you interested in playing a VR game, even if you don’t already own a headset?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Aimed to show us the general interest people have for a VR game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much do horror games appeal to you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much do puzzle games appeal to you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This goes even deeper into the two genres of the game. We want to see if they are of equal interest to our customers without one overpowering the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often do you play video games?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And when you are playing, how often is it that you are playing a horror video game?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you answered between 1 to 5 to the previous question, when do you prefer to play horror video games?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This categorises customers that will interact with our game on set times. We can use this information to market our game during these periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which of these features would make your gaming experience unique?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Segmenting by benefits sought shows us what experience would our customers want more. With that in mind we can push prioritised features first so that our game gains more following at launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What makes you lose interest in a video game far too early?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We also need to know the deal breakers for our clients. We want to make sure that people play our game for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What makes you invest in a video game?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This question is meant to reveal the factors that make our undecided clients push that “purchase” button. With that in mind, we can take certain actions, such as offer deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much would you be willing to spend on an indie VR game?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Straightforward question that will reveal if our price estimation was realistic enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there something else you wish to see in a VR video game?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Typical open question to make sure that no client input is left unheard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How old are you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Although not a behavioural question, this helps us identify age groups and see if responses vary from one to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;customer-detail---results&quot;&gt;Customer Detail - Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking over our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;28 responses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; submitted in the past week we can make the following conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although not many people own a VR headset, there was an overwhelmingly positive response to wanting to experiment our VR game. As VR headsets are getting more accessible, or easier to borrow, our game will surely get to our customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question4.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this question we were trying to verify if both game elements equally appeal to the players, making sure that neither of them retain them from playing the game. As it seems, they are quite balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question5.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question6.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question7.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we get from this part of the survey is that over 50% of people play video games weekly or even more frequently, but it’s not very often that it’s a horror game. That means that in our marketing strategy we should highlight that it has two genres, so that it appeals to both horror and non-horror gamers.
Moreover, when people are playing horror games they prefer doing it during the night, to enhance their experience. This leaves room for us to make certain decisions such as events or bonuses during nigh-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question8.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question8.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First to notice is that there is not much of an interest in having a pack of games. That means we will reconsider this after launching the game. Instead, we can focus on having consequences and unique horror through auditory-visual illusions.
There was a positive response to having a self paced game and having little to no instructions, which will definitely set us apart from the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question9.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question9.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, our main concerns with other VR video games align with our customers. This further confirms that our product is desired, and that delivering the features we intend to, will make customers spend more time in our game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question10.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question10.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what it seems, having a Halloween discount and making the game free for a period of time, will surely attract more customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question11.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question11.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The price range selected by more than 50% is our proposed price range or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/question13.jpg&quot; title=&quot;question13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;question13.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Variations between age groups were very little, which means that our customers act independently of their age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;customer-detail---conclusions&quot;&gt;Customer Detail - Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although some of our initial ideas like having a pack of games or catering the game to a horror audience didn’t translate as well as we thought, we were pretty aligned with what our customers want. Knowing what features they want to see more, makes us prioritise certain things for the Customer Validation Stage. We surely know what attracts customers, making our marketing strategy easier.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Milestone 2" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Project Description</title><link href="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project Description" /><published>2021-10-25T16:22:16+03:00</published><updated>2021-10-25T16:22:16+03:00</updated><id>https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://murderhotel.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll/">&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#roadmap&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-team&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-team&quot;&gt;The Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-problem&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#value-proposition&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-value-proposition&quot;&gt;Value Proposition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#customer-segments&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-customer-segments&quot;&gt;Customer Segments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#competition&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-competition&quot;&gt;Competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#advantage-over-the-competition&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-advantage-over-the-competition&quot;&gt;Advantage Over The Competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#key-metrics&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-key-metrics&quot;&gt;Key Metrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cost-structure&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-cost-structure&quot;&gt;Cost Structure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#revenue-streams&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-revenue-streams&quot;&gt;Revenue Streams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/roadmap.png&quot; title=&quot;roadmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;roadmap.png&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-team&quot;&gt;The Team&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Team.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Team.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Team.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video games are starting to feel stale nowadays. There can be no doubt that the entertainment industry could always benefit from innovative ideas and new twists on classic designs. We believe that the genre that benefits the most from virtual reality is horror. The extra immersion gained from a complete field of view serves to communicate fear and tension in a much more visceral way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;value-proposition&quot;&gt;Value Proposition&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By choosing to play our games, you have the get to experience a whole new reality. You move past the limits of the plastic frames around your screen and have the opportunity to truly interact with your environment and experience a character’s story first-hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;customer-segments&quot;&gt;Customer Segments&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We target a niche-market customer segment. Our customers are people who regularly play and enjoy either puzzle games, horror games or both and feel the need to elevate their experience. Moreover, those we target need to own a VR headset and a PC capable of running VR games. These restrictions mean that they are willing to spend a notable amount of money on their hobby, a fact that can be taken into consideration when developing a business model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;competition&quot;&gt;Competition&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row imager__plugin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Competition.png&quot; title=&quot;Competition.png&quot; alt=&quot;Competition.png&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;advantage-over-the-competition&quot;&gt;Advantage Over The Competition&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes a considerable time investment and a certain headspace to begin playing an AAA game. Sessions tend to only be fun if you have enough time to get completely immersed and absorbed into the experience, not to mention the high price point. AAA games need to be purchased every time one wants a new experience, and the financial investment can quickly add up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murder Hotel aims to be the base for a suite of similar, yet different bite sized games that can be purchased at lower price points, individually. Moreover, their short length and single-session play length allow this type of game to fit into a busy schedule much easier that an expensive, heavy AAA game would at a considerably lower price point. PC VR users do presumably have money to spend, but 5 AAA games can easily surpass the price of a headset while not offering much variety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;key-metrics&quot;&gt;Key Metrics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the fact that our long-term goal is to create an engaging suite of games based on the same principle, the aspects we should focus on are related to user gain and multiple games purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daily new users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daily active users (DAU)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monthly Active Users (MAU)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Returning users: users that purchased and played multiple games from us&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average Session Length: offers insight on the users’ attention span and engagement level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other metrics, based on a stable audience, are not applicable or relevant for puzzle games with a premium monetization scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cost-structure&quot;&gt;Cost Structure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product cost&lt;/strong&gt;: hardware (fixed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service cost&lt;/strong&gt;: software licenses (fixed), server maintenance (fixed), art &amp;amp; audio outsourcing (variable, need-based)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product line cost&lt;/strong&gt;: publisher commissions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer cost&lt;/strong&gt;: product returns (variable), physical deluxe editions (fixed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;revenue-streams&quot;&gt;Revenue Streams&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transaction-based revenue: the games will be sold premium, at a price point around 15€ in order to keep the commitment of buying another game low and encouraging customers to return to our games repeatedly, while still feeling that their spending is minimal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Milestone 1" /></entry></feed>